Ryan S. Rich

Product Designer

ryanSrich.com 503.334.9134

SKILLS

Product Design Design Management Design Direction Creative Direction Mobile Design Data Driven Design Responsive Design User Centered Design (UCD) Interaction Design Rapid Prototyping Wireframing Design Sprints **Usability Research** User Experience Design Journey Mapping User Interface Design HTML/CSS/JavaScript Angular JS Development

SOFTWARE

Ruby Development

Adobe Creative Suite Sketch Affinity Designer Framer Studio Git/Version Control Docker Highly skilled designer and developer with a penchant for creating quality software. Possesses a strong ability to lead technical and creative teams. Proven skills in user experience, front-end development, and user interface design.

EXPERIENCE

Director of Design at Catalyze, Inc.

Dec 2013 - Present

- Designed two first in class software platforms from the ground up.
- Built and led a team of UX Engineers, Product Designers and Developers.
- Worked directly under the Chief Product Officer to grow and expand enterprise product and services offering.
- Designed and developed several web properties including the core marketing site, developer resources, and compliance documentation.

Front-end Web Developer at Global Thinking

May 2013 - Dec 2013

- Worked with leading brands such as Audi, Volkswagen, and Ducati to build internal sales and marketing software.
- Designed websites, print, and digital collateral for a number of local DC organizations.
- Developed the front-end to several ruby on rails apps including those that power fortune 500 companies.

EDUCATION

R.I.T.

2010 - 2013

B.S. Applied Science

Onondaga CC

2008 - 2010

RECOGNITION

- Summa Cum Laude R.I.T. 2013
- Saunders Summer Start-up Program
- Three time R.I.T. 48 finisher
- First class participant in High Tech Rochester lean launchpad
- Selected as undergrad Design Associate to graduate communications
- 2013 DC Dribbble presenter

Co-founder at Gradesnap

March 2012 - May 2013

- Co-founded Gradesnap in late 2011 as a sophomore at R.I.T.
- Developed optical character recognition technology to assist grade school teachers with scoring multiple choice tests.
- Guided the company through two business accelerators and a seed round of funding.
- Designed and developed <u>gradespan.com</u>, the core brand, and all visual graphics.

Front-end Designer at Versal

November 2011 - March 2012

- Working directly under the CTO I helped rapidly design and develop web applications for demos, pitches, and seminars.
- Designed and built email templates, marketing webpages.

UX Designer at FFC

March. 2011 - November 2011

- Redesigned and developed the FFC mortgage web portal.
- Created digital icons, fonts and supporting graphics.